<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="GenesisSummary">The book of beginnings. The Book of Genesis has sometimes been called the "seed-plot" of the entire Bible. Most of the major doctrines in the Bible are introduced in "seed" form in the Book of Genesis.</string>
    <string name="ExodusSummary">The book of departure. In God\'s timing, the exodus of the Israelites from Egypt marked the end of a period of oppression for Abraham\'s descendants, and the beginning of the fulfillment of the covenant promise to Abraham that his descendants would not only live in the Promised Land, but would also multiply and become a great nation.</string>
    <string name="LeviticusSummary">The purpose of Leviticus is to provide instruction and laws to guide a sinful, yet redeemed people in their relationship with a holy God. There is an emphasis in Leviticus on the need for personal holiness in response to a holy God.</string>
    <string name="NumbersSummary">The message of the Book of Numbers is universal and timeless. It reminds believers of the spiritual warfare in which they are engaged, for Numbers is the book of the service and walk of God\'s people.</string>
    <string name="DeuteronomySummary">A new generation of Israelites was about to enter the Promised Land. The book of Deuteronomy was given to remind them of God\'s law and God\'s power.</string>
    <string name="JoshuaSummary">The Book of Joshua provides an overview of the military campaigns to conquer the land area that God had promised. Following the exodus from Egypt and the subsequent forty years of the wilderness wanderings, the newly-formed nation is now poised to enter the Promised Land.</string>
    <string name="JudgesSummary">The Book of Judges can be divided into two sections: 1) Chapters 1-16 which gives an account of the wars of deliverance beginning with the Israelites\' defeat of the Canaanites and ending with the defeat of the Philistines and the death of Samson; 2) Chapters 17-21 which is referred to as an appendix and does not relate to the previous chapters. These chapters are noted as a time "when there was no king in Israel".</string>
    <string name="RuthSummary">The Book of Ruth teachs genuine love and kindness will be rewarded. God abundantly blesses those who seek to live obedient lives.</string>
    <string name="Samuel1Summary">First Samuel records the history of Israel in the land of Canaan as they move from the rule of judges to being a unified nation under kings. Samuel emerges as the last judge, and he anoints the first two kings, Saul and David.</string>
    <string name="Samuel2Summary">2 Samuel is the record of King David\'s reign. This book places the Davidic Covenant in its historical context.</string>
    <string name="Kings1Summary">This book is the sequel to 1 and 2 Samuel and begins by tracing Solomon\'s rise to kingship after the death of David.</string>
    <string name="Kings2Summary">The Book of 2 Kings is a sequel to the Book of 1 Kings. It continues the story of the kings over the divided kingdom (Israel and Judah). The Book of 2 Kings concludes with the final overthrow and deportation of the people of Israel and Judah to Assyria and Babylon, respectively.</string>
    <string name="Chronicles1Summary">The Book of 1 Chronicles was written after the exile to help those returning to Israel understand how to worship God. The history focused on the Southern Kingdom, the tribes of Judah, Benjamin and Levi.</string>
    <string name="Chronicles2Summary">The Book of 2 Chronicles is essentially an evaluation of the nation\'s religious history.</string>
    <string name="EzraSummary">The emphasis in Ezra is on the rebuilding of the Temple. The book contains extensive genealogical records, principally for the purpose of establishing the claims to the priesthood on the part of the descendants of Aaron.</string>
    <string name="NehemiahSummary">The Book of Nehemiah, one of the history books of the Bible, continues the story of Israel\'s return from the Babylonian captivity and the rebuilding of the temple in Jerusalem.</string>
    <string name="EstherSummary">The purpose of the Book of Esther is to display the providence of God, especially in regard to His chosen people, Israel.</string>
    <string name="JobSummary">The Book of Job helps us to understand the suffering may sometimes be allowed in our lives to purify, test, teach or strengthen the soul. God remains enough, deserves and requests our love and praise in all circumstances of life.</string>
    <string name="PsalmSummary">The Book of Psalms is the longest book in the Bible, with 150 individual psalms. It is also one of the most diverse, since the psalms deal with such subjects as God and His creation, war, worship, wisdom, sin and evil, judgment, justice, and the coming of the Messiah.</string>
    <string name="ProverbsSummary">In the Book of Proverbs, Solomon reveals the mind of God in matters high and lofty and in common, ordinary, everyday situations, too. It appears that no topic escaped King Solomon\'s attention.</string>
    <string name="EcclesiastesSummary">Ecclesiastes is a book of perspective. This book gives Christians a chance to see the world through the eyes of a person who, though very wise, is trying to find meaning in temporary, human things.</string>
    <string name="SongOfSolomonSummary">The Song of Solomon is a lyric poem written to extol the virtues of love between a husband and his wife. The poem clearly presents marriage as God\'s design. A man and woman are to live together within the context of marriage, loving each other spiritually, emotionally, and physically.</string>
    <string name="IsaiahSummary">Isaiah proclaimed a message of repentance from sin and hopeful expectation of God\'s deliverance in the future.</string>
    <string name="JeremiahSummary">Jeremiah calls out for the nation to turn back to God. At the same time, Jeremiah recognizes the inevitability of Judah\'s destruction due to its unrepentant idolatry and immorality.</string>
    <string name="LamentationsSummary">The Prophet Jeremiah wrote the Book of Lamentations as a lament for what occurred to Judah and Jerusalem.</string>
    <string name="EzekielSummary">Ezekiel attempted to bring to his generation immediate repentance and to confidence in the distant future.</string>
    <string name="DanielSummary">Daniel served in the royal court of Nebuchadnezzar and several rulers who followed Nebuchadnezzar. The Book of Daniel records the actions, prophecies, and visions of the Prophet Daniel.</string>
    <string name="HoseaSummary">Hosea wrote this book to remind the Israelites — and us — that ours is a loving God whose loyalty to His covenant people is unwavering.</string>
    <string name="JoelSummary">Joel symbolically describes the locusts as a marching human army and views all of this as divine judgment coming against the nation for her sins.</string>
    <string name="AmosSummary">Amos\' mission is directed to his neighbor to the north, Israel. His messages of impending doom and captivity for the nation because of her sins are largely unpopular and unheeded.</string>
    <string name="ObadiahSummary">Obadiah is a prophet of God who uses this opportunity to condemn Edom for sins against both God and Israel.</string>
    <string name="JonahSummary">Disobedience and revival are the key themes in this book. Jonah\'s experience in the belly of the whale provides him with a unique opportunity to seek a unique deliverance, as he repents during this equally unique retreat.</string>
    <string name="MicahSummary">The message of the Book of Micah is a complex mixture of judgment and hope. The messages of hope and doom are not necessarily contradictory, however, since restoration and transformation take place only after judgment.</string>
    <string name="NahumSummary">Nahum was telling the people of Judah to not despair because God had pronounced judgment and the Assyrians would soon be getting just what they deserved.</string>
    <string name="HabakkukSummary">Habakkuk was wondering why God was allowing His chosen people to go through the current suffering at the hands of their enemies. God answers and Habakkuk\'s faith is restored.</string>
    <string name="ZephaniahSummary">Zephaniah\'s message is that God is sovereign over all nations and the wicked will be punished and the righteous will be vindicated on the day of judgment. Also, God blesses those who repent and trust in Him.</string>
    <string name="HaggaiSummary">The Book of Haggai is a reminder of the problems the people of God faced at this time, how the people courageously trusted in God and how God provided for their needs.</string>
    <string name="ZechariahSummary">Zechariah emphasized that God has used His prophets to teach, warn and correct His people. Unfortunately, they refused to listen.</string>
    <string name="MalachiSummary">The Book of Malachi is an oracle: "The word of the Lord to Israel through Malachi" (1:1). This was God\'s warning through Malachi to tell the people to turn back to God.</string>
    <string name="MatthewSummary">Matthew intends to prove to the Jews that Jesus Christ is the promised Messiah. More than any other gospel, Matthew quotes the Old Testament to show how Jesus fulfilled the words of the Jewish prophets.</string>
    <string name="MarkSummary">Mark\'s gospel appears to be targeted to the Roman believers, particularly Gentiles. Mark wrote as a pastor to Christians who previously had heard and believed the Gospel (Romans 1:8).</string>
    <string name="LukeSummary">Luke\'s gospel is unique in that is a meticulous history often giving details the other accounts omit.</string>
    <string name="JohnSummary">John\'s purpose is not to present a chronological narrative of the life of Christ, but to display His deity. John emphasized Jesus Christ as "the Son of God", fully God and fully man.</string>
    <string name="ActsSummary">The Book of Acts was written to provide a history of the early church. The book of Acts emphasizes the importance of obedience to God\'s Word and the transformation that occurs as a result of knowing Christ.</string>
    <string name="RomansSummary">As with all Paul\'s epistles to the churches, his purpose in writing was to proclaim the glory of the Lord Jesus Christ by teaching doctrine and edify and encourage the believers who would receive his letter.</string>
    <string name="Corinthians1Summary">The apostle Paul wrote his first letter to the Corinthians in an attempt to restore the Corinthian church to its foundation: Jesus Christ.</string>
    <string name="Corinthians2Summary">Paul was overjoyed to learn from Titus that the majority of Corinthians repented of their rebellion against Paul. The apostle encourages them for this in an expression of his genuine love.</string>
    <string name="GalatiansSummary">Galatians was not written as an essay in contemporary history. It was a protest against corruption of the gospel of Christ. The essential truth of justification by faith rather than by the works of the law had been obscured by the Judaizers\' insistence that believers in Christ must keep the law if they expected to be perfect before God.</string>
    <string name="EphesiansSummary">The aim of this epistle is to confirm and to equip a maturing church. It presents a balanced view of the body of Christ and its importance.</string>
    <string name="PhilippiansSummary">This is a tender letter to a group of Christians who were especially close to the heart of Paul, and comparatively little is said about doctrinal error.</string>
    <string name="ColossiansSummary">The Book of Colossians is a mini-ethics course, addressing every area of Christian life. The theme of this book is the sufficiency of our Lord, Jesus Christ, in meeting our needs in every area.</string>
    <string name="Thessalonians1Summary">In the church of Thessalonica there were some misunderstandings about the return of Christ. Paul desired to clear them up in his letter. He also writes it as an instruction in holy living.</string>
    <string name="Thessalonians2Summary">The church in Thessalonica still had some misconceptions about the Day of the Lord. They thought it had come already so they stopped with their work. They were being persecuted badly. Paul wrote to clear up misconceptions and to comfort them.</string>
    <string name="Timothy1Summary">This letter lays the foundation for ordaining elders, and provides guidance for ordaining people into offices of the church. In essence, 1 Timothy is a leadership manual for church organization and administration.</string>
    <string name="Timothy2Summary">Paul wanted to use his last words to encourage Timothy, and all other believers, to persevere in faith and proclaim the gospel of Jesus Christ.</string>
    <string name="TitusSummary">This letter advises Titus regarding what qualifications to look for in leaders for the church. Paul continued to disciple Titus and others as they grew in the grace of the Lord.</string>
    <string name="PhilemonSummary">The letter to Philemon is the shortest of all Paul\'s writings and deals with the practice of slavery. Paul wanted Philemon to accept Onesimus as a brother in Christ and not merely as a slave.</string>
    <string name="HebrewsSummary">Many of the early Jewish believers were slipping back into the rites and rituals of Judaism in order to escape the mounting persecution. This letter, then, is an exhortation for those persecuted believers to continue in the grace of Jesus Christ.</string>
    <string name="JamesSummary">The Book of James is directed to Jewish Christians scattered among all the nations. James was writing to Jews to encourage them to continue growing in this new Christian faith.</string>
    <string name="Peter1Summary">1 Peter is a letter from Peter to the believers who had been dispersed throughout the ancient world and were under intense persecution.</string>
    <string name="Peter2Summary">Peter was alarmed that false teachers were beginning to infiltrate the churches. He called on Christians to grow and become strong in their faith so that they could detect and combat the spreading apostasy.</string>
    <string name="John1Summary">The key purpose of 1 John is to set boundaries on the content of faith and to give believers assurance of their salvation.</string>
    <string name="John2Summary">The Book of 2 John is a strong warning to be on the lookout for deceivers who were going about saying that Christ had not actually risen in the flesh.</string>
    <string name="John3Summary">John writes to commend and encourage his beloved co-worker, Gaius. He indirectly warns and condemns the behavior of one Diotrephes. And he commends the example of Demetrius who was reported as having a good testimony from all.</string>
    <string name="JudeSummary">Jude writes that evil works are the evidence of apostasy. He admonishes us to contend for the faith, for there are tares among the wheat.</string>
    <string name="RevelationSummary">The Revelation of Jesus Christ was given to John by God "to show his servants what must soon take place."</string>
</resources>
